# Venuprasad Naik

## **Core Java Developer (Consultant)**

Inquisitive Programmer with experience of 3 years 4 months in Software Development. Skilled in Core Java, Spring Framework, SQL, Microsoft Azure, Object-Oriented Programming (OOP), Maven, and React.js. I keep myself updated with new technologies and try to produce optimal code solutions. At Mercedes-Benz Research and Development received the Young Achiever of the Year award.

vpnaik97@gmail.com +91 72598 16840

linkedin.com/in/venuprasad

### WORK EXPERIENCE

## Mercedes-Benz Research and Development India

Core Java Developer (Consultant)

Jul 2019 - current

- Working on developing an In-house software application for ECU Development that operates 24x7
- Worked with cross competency teams to address business needs and system design. Technical solution design and development through implementation, usually focused on one module/system/service.
- Tech Stack: Core Java, Spring Framework, MS-SQL, Maven, JFrog, Jenkins, Git, SonarQube
- Developed IAM OIDC login for web applications using Spring Framework
- Worked on several backend code refactoring, optimisation and performance improvement tasks
- Developed maven library for parsing Metadata Exchange Format (MDX) and XML data from scratch
- Produced High-Quality software that has tested, code reviewed, analysed in sonar and checked in regularly for Continuous Integration
- Automated maven artefacts pipeline that reduced deployment speed from 30 min to 2.5 min
- Conducting code reviews, checking for adherence to standard methodologies and best practices.

#### Software Developer (GET)

Aug 2018 - Jul 2019

- Front End Developer for Developing a Web Application in React.js Framework with MobX.js and Axios.js
- Developed an Analytical and Monitoring application for providing cloud-based billing solution using React.js, JSON, Fluent UI
- Worked on Power BI integration for Web Application
- Experience in working with Azure Cloud and Web API

## AquaSafi Purification Systems

Mobile Application Developer (Intern)

Jun 2017 - May 2018

- Built an Android Application from scratch for Water ATM using NFC, MifareClassic, ACR122u, java, SQLite, XML
- Developed OTP based Authentication for Android Application
- Worked on usage report generation and data sync to cloud

#### **SKILLS**

- Core Java
- Spring Framework
- Data Structure
- OOP
- SQL
- React.js
- Microsoft Azure
- Maven
- Jenkins
- Git

#### **EDUCATION**

## **Bachelor of Engineering**

B V B College of

Engineering& Technology

Computer Science and Engineering

2014 – 2018

Hubli, Karnataka

CGPA: 8.58

## **CERTIFICATIONS**

Problem Solving (Advanced)

Hacker Rank

SQL (Intermediate)

Hacker Rank

**Advanced Java Programming** 

inkedIr

Data Structures & Algorithms

edX with Georgia Tech